here is the simplest set of steps for a
perfect deadlift that you will ever see
first approach the bar so that your
shins are one inch away from the barbell
placing the bar directly over the middle
of your foot and then slightly turn your
toes outward the width of your stance
should be the same that you would use
for a maximal vertical jump step two
without bending your knees forward bend
over and grab the barbell just on the
outside of your legs when you do this
there should still be an inch between
your shins and the bar step three bend
your knees forward until your shins meet
the barbell dropping your hips down into
position step four flatten your back
think about dropping your belly down
between your legs you should feel a
little bit of the weight of the bar in
your hands fix your eyesight on an
object to 12 to 15 feet in front of you
push your knees out into your forearms
and then drag the barbell directly up
your legs until you're standing straight
up with your hips pushed through your
chest pushed through and your shoulders
held back then lower the bar the exact
same way that you picked it up down your
legs and to the floor this is known as
the starting strength method